Rockwell Kent
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Alphabetical Files, circa 1900-1971, undated, Series 1:; (Reels 5153-5249, 5256, 5740-5741)
  - McDonald, J. N., 1915 (Reel 5211, Frame 721-726)
  - McFarlane, John W., 1965-1966 (Reel 5211, Frame 727-731)
  - McGaulley, Grace, 1948 (Reel 5211, Frame 732-735)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc., 1942, 1966 (Reel 5211, Frame 736-739)
  - McGuire, Harry, 1943 (Reel 5211, Frame 740-744)
  - McInerney, T. J., 1946, 1957 (Reel 5211, Frame 745-748)
  - McIntire, Gordon, 1958-1959 (Reel 5211, Frame 749-754)
  - McIntyre, Robert G., 1963 (Reel 5211, Frame 755-764)
  - McIver, J. D., 1939 (Reel 5211, Frame 765-768)
  - McKay, Louis D., 1939 (Reel 5211, Frame 769-772)
  - McKenzie, Frances C., 1941-1942 (Reel 5211, Frame 773-781)
  - McLellan, Hugh, 1935 (Reel 5211, Frame 782-792)
  - McManus, John T., 1961 (Reel 5211, Frame 793-796)
  - McMichael, Jack R., Jr., 1941 (Reel 5211, Frame 797-802)
  - McNeer, May (see: Ward, Lynd, and May McNeer) (Reel 5211)
  - McNeilly, John C., 1941 (Reel 5211, Frame 803-806)
  - McPherson, J., 1911, 1915 (Reel 5211, Frame 807-813)
  - McQuillan, Mr., 1943 (Reel 5211, Frame 814-816)
  - McVey, William M., 1941 (Reel 5211, Frame 817-820)
  - Mead, Dr. Margaret, 1961 (Reel 5211, Frame 821-825)
  - Medallic Art Co., 1938-1960 (Reel 5211, Frame 826-854)
    (orders to cast medals and requests for price information)
  - Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy (see: Radical Groups--Spain) (Reel 5211)
  - Medichiva, Kaleria, undated, 1965-1969 (Reel 5211, Frame 855-916)
  - Melish, Rev. William Howard and Mary Jane, undated, 1956-1969 (Reel 5211, Frame 917-954)
  - Melton, Robert and Elizabeth, 1955-1956, 1964-1968 (Reel 5211, Frame 955-1050)
    (correspondence praising Kent's books from a hand binder interested in binding special editions; request for design suitable for stamping on leather bindings)
  - Meltzer, Charles Henry, 1921 (Reel 5211, Frame 1051-1054)
  - Memoranda, 1942-1960, undated (Reel 5211, Frame unfilmed)
    (notes, lists, doodles, fragments of writings, addresses and phone numbers, and some clippings)
  - Memorial Portfolio, 1971 (Reel 5211, Frame 1055-1204)
  - Menihan, John C. and Marge, undated, 1947 (Reel 5211, Frame 1205-1209)
  - Menus (Reel 5211, Frame unfilmed)
  - Mercer, Jack, 1969 (Reel 5211, Frame 1210-1213)
  - Merkle, Edward, 1941 (Reel 5211, Frame 1214-1217)
    (letters of reference for former employee)
  - Merrill, Lewis and Bobbie, 1941-1950 (Reel 5211, Frame 1218-1418)
    (correspondence about United Office and Professional Workers of America, organized labor, politics, social activities, and news of mutual friends)
  - Merritt, C. C., 1948 (Reel 5211, Frame 1419-1422)
  - Mershaw Publishing Corporation, 1951 (Reel 5211, Frame 1423-1425)
  - Meserole, Darwin J., 1951-1952 (Reel 5211, Frame 1426-1449)
    (typescript of article on fascism in the U.S., and related correspondence)
  - Metcalf, Kathryn E., 1963 (Reel 5211, Frame 1450-1454)
  - Metropolitan Library Council, 1942 (Reel 5211, Frame 1455-1457)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1927-1928, 1941-1942 (Reel 5211, Frame 1458-1488)
    (correspondence about reproduction permission and Kent's displeasure at the manner in which the museum handled requests from publishers; printed matter describing labor union program and letter to director complimenting the program; see also: Burroughs, Bryson)
  - Metzger, Libby, 1941 (Reel 5211, Frame 1489-1492)
  - Mexican Art Workshop, 1948 (Reel 5211, Frame 1493-1498)
  - Mexico Trip, 1955 (Reel 5211, Frame 1499-1503)
  - Meyer, Dr., 1954 (Reel 5211, Frame 1504-1506)
  - Meyerovitch, Mr., 1943 (Reel 5211, Frame 1507-1510)
  - Meynell, Sir Francis, 1949-1969 (Reel 5211, Frame 1511-1533)
  - Michael, Mr., 1963 (Reel 5211, Frame 1534-1536)
  - Middleton, Mary, 1956 (Reel 5211, Frame 1537-1543)
  - Middleton, R. Hunter, 1944-1960 (Reel 5212, Frame 3-69)
    (correspondence about Bewick blocks printed by Middleton, arrangements for Society of Typographic Arts to issue a Kent print, and book design)
  - Milestone, Kendall [sister of Frances Kent], 1936-1948 (Reel 5212, Frame 70-209)
    (correspondence with Otto Boehm, manager of Kenstone, the Milestone's farm, about dairy business and finances; family news, and Kent exhibition at Stendahl Galleries; see also: Lee Family)
  - Milgrom, Sam, 1948-1959 (Reel 5212, Frame 210-229)
    (news of mutual friends; see also: International Workers Order)
  - Milk License, 1944, 1946 (Reel 5212, Frame unfilmed)
  - Milk Strike, 1941 (Reel 5212, Frame 230-317)
    (correspondence and printed matter)
  - Miller, Albina, undated (Reel 5212, Frame 318-321)
  - Miller, Burr, 1966-1967 (Reel 5212, Frame 322-334)
  - Miller, Elsie Marie, 1941 (Reel 5212, Frame 335-340)
  - Miller, George C., 1928-1962 (Reel 5212, Frame 379-469)
    (orders for lithographic prints and discussion of technical specifications)
  - Miller, Kenneth Hayes, 1912-1915 (Reel 5212, Frame 341-378)
    (letters about literature, Kent's omission from Armory Show, family news, and comments about sale of Kent painting to Arthur Jerome Eddy)
  - Miller, Leon Gordon, 1947, 1953 (Reel 5212, Frame 470-474)
  - Miller, Malcolm, 1941 (Reel 5212, Frame 475-479)
  - Miller, Tom and Helen, 1956 (Reel 5212, Frame 480-484)
  - Miller's High Life Beer Co., 1948 (Reel 5212, Frame 485-487)
  - Millet, Martha, 1952 (Reel 5212, Frame 488-492)
  - Milton, David, 1951-1952 (Reel 5212, Frame 493-503)
  - Milwaukee Art Institute, 1934 (Reel 5212, Frame 504-509)
    (list of paintings to be forwarded from Art Institute of Chicago for exhibition in Milwaukee, and letter from museum director about insurance and sales commissions)
  - Minerly, Mr. and Mrs. John P., 1968-1969 (Reel 5212, Frame 510-515)
  - The Minneapolis Institute of Arts, 1941 (Reel 5212, Frame 516-518)
  - Minnesota Broadcasting Corporation, 1941 (Reel 5212, Frame 519-526)
  - Minor, Lydia, undated, 1954-1960 (Reel 5212, Frame 527-533)
  - Moby Dick, undated, 1929-1969 (Reel 5212, Frame 534-643)
    (page proofs (4 pp.); correspondence concerning copyrights and reproduction permissions)
  - Model, Roland & Stone, 1954-1967 (Reel 5212, Frame unfilmed)
    (correspondence with stockbroker; receipts for shares traded, and monthly statements)
  - The Modern School, 1941 (Reel 5212, Frame 644-646)
  - Moe, Evelyn, 1942 (Reel 5212, Frame 647-650)
  - Moldovan, Dr. Alfred and Jean, 1955 (Reel 5212, Frame 651-655)
  - Moller Tryggve Juul, undated, 1948 (Reel 5212, Frame 656-668)
  - Molyneaux, Jane and Abram, 1960-1965 (Reel 5212, Frame 669-676)
  - Monaco, Arto C., 1937-1957, 1963-1966, undated (Reel 5212, Frame 677-1023)
    (correspondence about starting a career as a cartoonist in Hollywood, beginnings of Screen Cartoon Guild, attempts to find publisher for Louis Monaco's book, Experiences in Army Ordnance Training Unit during World War II, art for propaganda exhibition, Monaco toy business, news of family and friends, problems at Santa's Workshop, Inc.; printed matter, including cartoons for military training, catalogs of Monaco toys, and promotional brochures for Santa Claus Village; see also: Toy Business)
  - Monaco, Arto C., cont. (Reel 5213, Frame 3-135)
  - Monaco, Jimmy, 1940-1945, undated (Reel 5213, Frame 136-177)
    (letters of recommendation, correspondence with Monaco in Army Air Corps during World War II, with news of family and friends)
  - Monaco, Louis, Ida, and Levin, 1936-1946 (Reel 5213, Frame 178-215)
    (correspondence regarding publication of Monaco's book, farm and restaurant business, letters and cards from Monaco trip to Florida)
  - Monhegan, 1947-1958, 1969-1970 (Reel 5213, Frame 216-799)
    (correspondence about repairs, maintenance, and summer rental of cottage, and its subsequent sale; correspondence with island friends, and about murder of Mae See; map and snapshot of the house; see also: Fitzgerald, James; Moran, Sally (Mae See))
  - Monigotti, Elena, 1958 (Reel 5213, Frame 800-805)
  - The Montclair Art Museum, 1956 (Reel 5213, Frame 806-809)
  - Montgomery Ward, 1937-1951 (Reel 5213, Frame unfilmed)
    (orders for household goods, tools, and clothing)
  - Monthly Review, 1951, 1953 (Reel 5213, Frame 810-814)
  - Monthly Statements, 1946 (Reel 5213, Frame unfilmed)
    (dairy business)
  - Moody, Howard E. and Clara, 1970 (Reel 5213, Frame 815-821)
  - Moore, John G., 1955-1968, undated (Reel 5213, Frame 822-1066)
    (fan letters; correspondence about politics, poetry, art, Kent's gift to the USSR, and America's social problems)
  - Moore, Dr. Merrill, 1935-1958, undated (Reel 5213, Frame 1067-1372)
    (correspondence with psychiatrist friend about problems of family members; arrangements for having psychiatric patients board and work at Asgaard, with reports on individual cases; plans for Kent Collection; news of Moore's experiences in military during World War II)
  - Moorhead, Harley G., 1941 (Reel 5213, Frame 1373-1377)
  - Moos, Elizabeth, undated, 1941-1970 (Reel 5213, Frame 1378-1410)
  - Moran, Sally (Mae See), 1947-1953 (Reel 5213, Frame 1411-1548)
    (correspondence, mainly concerning arrangements to move to Kent cottage on Monhegan; a few letters sent by friends and neighbors after Moran's death; newspaper clippings speculating whether the death was murder or suicide; see also: Monhegan; and Sweeties)
  - Morant, Dick, undated (Reel 5213, Frame 1549-1553)
  - Morant, Willie and Nick, 1960 (Reel 5214, Frame 3-7)
  - Moreau, John, 1964 (Reel 5214, Frame 8-10)
  - Morford, Rev. Richard A. and Aileen, 1951, 1960-1961 (Reel 5214, Frame 11-16)
  - Morgan, Ernst, 1944 (Reel 5214, Frame 17-20)
  - Morhouse, Margo, 1963-1966 (Reel 5214, Frame 21-29)
  - Mories, Fred G., 1927-1931, undated (Reel 5214, Frame 30-50)
    (mainly about social engagements; letter about plans to open an art school in Paris with Henry Davenport, and a comment about Ernest Lawson, who occupied the studio downstairs)
  - Morningstar, Percy, 1945, 1947 (Reel 5214, Frame 51-54)
  - Morphy, Katherine M., 1947 (Reel 5214, Frame 55-59)
  - Morris, William, 1934 (Reel 5214, Frame 60-95)
    (correspondence about proposed broadcasts from Greenland, publication of pamphlet, and series of articles on Greenland by Kent for Esquire magazine)
  - Morrison, Aileen, 1947 (Reel 5214, Frame 96-98)
  - Morrison, Anne, 1965-1966 (Reel 5214, Frame 99-103)
  - Morse, Alexander B., 1959 (Reel 5214, Frame 104-107)
  - Mortello, Domenico, 1941 (Reel 5214, Frame 108-113)
  - Mortgage and Tax Receipts, Inheritance Statements, etc., 1947-1949 (Reel 5214, Frame unfilmed)
  - Morton, Mr., undated (Reel 5214, Frame 114-116)
  - Moscow News, 1965 (Reel 5214, Frame 117-119)
  - Moses, Theo. W., 1921 (Reel 5214, Frame 120-122)
  - Moss, Al, and Gertrude Elowitz (see also: Elowitz, Gertrude, and Al Moss), 1948-1949, 1956-1957 (Reel 5214, Frame 123-150)
  - Motive, 1941 (Reel 5214, Frame 151-155)
  - Motor Boating, 1945 (Reel 5214, Frame 156-158)
  - Mount Holyoke College, 1941 (Reel 5214, Frame 159-162)
  - Mount Royal Hotel, 1952 (Reel 5214, Frame 163-165)
  - Mowat, Farley, 1970 (Reel 5214, Frame 166-172)
  - Muller, Charles, 1941 (Reel 5214, Frame 173-177)
  - Mumford, Lewis, 1965-1966 (Reel 5214, Frame 178-189)
  - The Municipal Broadcasting Station (WNYC), 1946 (Reel 5214, Frame 190-194)
  - Murayev, Dmitri, 1961 (Reel 5214, Frame 195-250)
    (correspondence with Soviet cultural attach, mainly concerning social events, request for help in sending Kent manuscripts to the USSR)
  - Murder, 1950-1951 (Reel 5214, Frame 251-274)
    (correspondence with FBI, local police, and graphologist regarding anonymous death threat against Kent; see also: "Hate" Mail)
  - Murphy, James P. J., 1948 (Reel 5214, Frame 275-279)
  - Murphy, Roy, undated (Reel 5214, Frame 280-283)
  - Murray Amendment, 1940 (Reel 5214, Frame 284-314)
    (correspondence with elected officials in support of increased funding for WPA)
  - The Museum of Modern Art, 1941-1942 (Reel 5214, Frame 315-326)
  - Unidentified and Illegible (Reel 5214, Frame 327-333)
    (F [E?]. M., undated; Lydia G. M., 1953)
  - Naiman, Max, undated (Reel 5214, Frame 334-337)
  - "Nana", 1934 (Reel 5214, Frame 338-342)
    (about Kent woodcut of Anna Sten in the role of "Nana")
  - The Nation, 1942-1943 (Reel 5214, Frame 343-347)
  - The National Academy of Arts and Letters, 1965 (Reel 5214, Frame 348-355)
  - National Academy of Design, 1940-1956, 1962 (Reel 5214, Frame 356-385)
    (invitations to exhibit and notification of election; printed matter)
  - National Advertising Art Center, Inc., 1947 (Reel 5214, Frame 386-390)
  - National Alliance of Art and Industry, 1939 (Reel 5214, Frame 391-408)
    (correspondence about Christmas card design)
  - National "Americans All" Week, 1941 (Reel 5214, Frame 409-414)
  - National Art School, 1948 (Reel 5214, Frame 415-421)
  - National Art Society, 1939 (Reel 5214, Frame 422-456)
    (correspondence about "Art for Your Sake" radio broadcast)
  - The National Arts Club, 1940 (Reel 5214, Frame 457-459)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1957 (Reel 5214, Frame 460-463)
  - National Broadcasting Company, Inc. (NBC), 1940-1970 (Reel 5214, Frame 464-495)
    (correspondence about programming)
  - The National Cancer Foundation, 1946 (Reel 5214, Frame 496-514)
  - The National Committee for Music Appreciation, 1940 (Reel 5214, Frame 515-519)
  - National Committee for People's Rights, 1938-1942 (Reel 5214, Frame 520-705)
    (printed matter, reports, minutes; correspondence with officers about administrative matters and activities on behalf of miners with lung disease)
  - National Committee for the Defense of Political Prisoners (see: Radical Groups--Political Prisoners) (Reel 5214)
  - National Conference of Christians & Jews, 1940 (Reel 5214, Frame 706-739)
  - National Conference of Social Work, 1941 (Reel 5214, Frame 740-744)
  - National Consumers League, 1940 (Reel 5214, Frame 745-750)
  - National Council for Federal Health Security, undated (Reel 5214, Frame 751-754)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, Inc., 1943-1959 (Reel 5214, Frame 755-1557)
    (correspondence about: fund-raising activities and cultural events, art committee plans for exhibition and cultural exchange, disarmament, arrangements for speaking engagements and meeting plans, Kent's peace stamp, and Kent gift of paintings to the USSR; also, printed matter, publicity releases, form letters to general membership and executive board, and report)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, Inc., cont. 1959-1964 (Reel 5215, Frame 2-1575)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, Inc., cont. 1964-1971 (Reel 5216, Frame 4-1069)
  - National Council of the Arts, Sciences and Professions, 1948-1949 (Reel 5216, Frame 1070-1124)
    (correspondence concerning Kent speech and McCarthyism; printed matter related to annual meeting; see also: Culture)
  - National Council to Combat Blindness, Inc., undated; 1947-1948 (Reel 5216, Frame 1125-1135)
  - National Emergency Conference for Democratic Rights (FBI) [National Federation for Constitutional Liberties], 1939-1940 (Reel 5216, Frame 1136-1172)
    (printed matter, including "Conference Statement on the Menace of the F.B.I.")
  - National Emergency Conference on Jobs and Security, 1945 (Reel 5216, Frame 1173-1189)
  - National Federation for Constitutional Liberties, 1940-1946, undated (Reel 5216, Frame 1190-1344)
    (mainly printed matter, including form letters to general membership; letters of endorsement from Kent appealing for funding of federation; see also: National Emergency Conference for Democratic Rights)
  - National Foundation for Asthmatic Children, 1956 (Reel 5216, Frame 1345-1347)
  - National Gallery of Art, 1941 (Reel 5216, Frame 1348-1351)
  - National Gallery of Contemporary Art, 1927 (Reel 5216, Frame 1352-1393)
    (proposed preamble, prospectus, constitution, bylaws, and certificate of incorporation; clippings; note from Eugenie Heller in support of project, and letter to Emilie Grigsby outlining plans for the Gallery; see also: Contemporary Art, Gallery of)
  - National Geographic, 1941 (Reel 5216, Frame 1394-1409)
  - National Gray's Harbor Committee, 1940 (Reel 5216, Frame 1410-1454)
    (form letters and printed matter regarding civil rights)
  - National Guardian, 1951-1952, 1957 (Reel 5216, Frame 1455-1468)
  - The National Hotel Company, 1940, 1942 (Reel 5216, Frame 1469-1479)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters (see also: The American Academy of Arts and Letters and The National Institute of Arts and Letters), 1965-1970 (Reel 5216, Frame 1480-1502)
  - National Jewish Black Book Committee, 1946 (Reel 5216, Frame 1503-1505)
  - National Joint Committee for Spanish Relief, 1941 (Reel 5216, Frame 1506-1508)
  - National Labor Committee Against War, 1941 (Reel 5216, Frame 1509-1544)
    (publications, reports, and form letters to general membership)
  - National League of American Pen Women, 1941 (Reel 5216, Frame 1545-1547)
  - National Maritime Union of America, 1940 (Reel 5216, Frame 1548-1565)
    (correspondence about murals for the union's new headquarters; request from Joseph Hirsch to be considered for the commission, and letter from Kent to Hugo Gellert expressing disappointment in the finished mural; printed matter; invitations to special events; arrangements for exhibition of Soviet posters)
  - National Maritime Union of America, cont. (Reel 5217, Frame 3-97)
  - National Negro Congress, 1940-1947 (Reel 5217, Frame 98-105)
  - National Organization for Public Health Nursing, Inc., 1946 (Reel 5217, Frame 106-108)
  - National Public Housing Conference, 1941 (Reel 5217, Frame 109-112)
  - National Publicity Council, 1946 (Reel 5217, Frame 113-118)
  - The National Ralph Cheney Defense Committee, 1940 (Reel 5217, Frame 119-124)
  - National Recreation Association, 1933, 1945 (Reel 5217, Frame 125-128)
  - National Resources Planning Board, 1941 (Reel 5217, Frame 129-132)
  - National St. Lawrence Association, 1944-1949 (Reel 5217, Frame 133-214)
    (printed matter and form letters to general membership)
  - National Sharecroppers Week, 1940-1941 (Reel 5217, Frame 215-225)
  - National Soap Sculpture Committee, 1941 (Reel 5217, Frame 226-228)
  - National Society for the Prevention of Blindness, 1939-1947 (Reel 5217, Frame 229-297)
    (correspondence concerning design for fund-raising brochure, copyright ownership, and request to adapt illustration; printed matter)
  - The National Society of Mural Painters, 1940-1941 (Reel 5217, Frame 298-306)
  - National Student Conference for Peace, Academic Freedom & Equality, undated (Reel 5217, Frame 307-310)
  - National Tuberculosis Association, 1937-1946 (Reel 5217, Frame 311-481)
    (correspondence concerning Kent's design for the 1939 Christmas seal; sample seals; see also: Tuberculosis Association)
  - National U.S.O. Campaign, 1941 (Reel 5217, Frame 482-484)
  - National War Poster Competition, 1942 (Reel 5217, Frame 485-495)
  - National Youth Administration, 1940 (Reel 5217, Frame 496-499)
  - Nations Credit Syndicate, 1937 (Reel 5217, Frame 500-505)
  - Nazarian, Richard, 1965-1968 (Reel 5217, Frame 506-533)
  - Nearing, Scott and Helen, 1953-1971 (Reel 5217, Frame 534-720)
    (correspondence about the Nearings' and Kent's writings; pacifist group being organized by the Nearings; printed matter about Social Science Institute with lists of its publications)
  - Needleman, Isidore G., 1959 (Reel 5217, Frame 721-724)
  - Negro Publication Society of America, 1941 (Reel 5217, Frame 725-735)
  - Nelson, Edward, 1918 (Reel 5217, Frame 736-738)
  - Nelson, George A., 1946-1953 (Reel 5217, Frame 739-749)
  - Nelson, Steve, 1956 (Reel 5217, Frame 750-753)
  - Nelson, Truman and Helen, 1941, 1952-1954 (Reel 5217, Frame 754-763)
  - Neutrality Act, 1938 (Reel 5217, Frame 764-801)
    (text of bill; letters from elected officials in reply to Kent's request that Congress not aid Japanese invasion of China [many signatures clipped])
  - New Age Gallery, 1945-1953 (Reel 5217, Frame 802-834)
    (printed matter including annual report, checklists of exhibitions, and form letters to shareholders and exhibitors)
  - New Century Publishers, 1945, 1960 (Reel 5217, Frame 835-839)
  - New Directions, 1941-1951 (Reel 5217, Frame 840-888)
    (about illustrations for Faust)
  - New England Color Studio, 1948 (Reel 5217, Frame 889-891)
  - New Frontiers, 1953 (Reel 5217, Frame 892-894)
  - New House, 1969-1970 (Reel 5217, Frame 895-902)
  - New Jersey Philatelic Federation, Inc., 1939 (Reel 5217, Frame 903-905)
  - New Jersey State Museum, 1936 (Reel 5217, Frame 906-909)
  - New Masses, 1935-1947, undated (Reel 5217, Frame 910-1274)
    (correspondence about unionization of artists, articles and letters to the editor by Kent with responses from readers, commissions for cover designs, speaking engagements, Art Young memorial, people's art, role of artist in wartime propaganda; miscellaneous printed matter including solicitations, subscription information, and advertising)
  - The New Republic, 1947 (Reel 5217, Frame 1275-1277)
  - New Rochelle Public Library, 1938 (Reel 5217, Frame 1278-1281)
  - The New School, 1949-1950 (Reel 5217, Frame 1282-1286)
  - The New Society of Artists, 1924 (Reel 5217, Frame 1287-1289)
  - New Theatre Center, 1941 (Reel 5217, Frame 1290-1293)
  - New Voices, 1943 (Reel 5217, Frame 1294-1297)
  - New World Review, undated, 1951-1971 (Reel 5217, Frame 1298-1534)
    (correspondence with editor Jessica Smith regarding: illustration, publication, and distribution of book commemorating the 35th anniversary of the Russian Revolution; arrangements for speaking engagement; Smith's comments on Kent's autobiography and its reviews; Kent's comments on articles appearing in the magazine; and proposal to Cyrus Eaton for new magazine on East-West relations; news of mutual friends; gift of Kent paintings to the USSR)
  - New World Review, cont. (Reel 5218, Frame 3-545)
  - New Year's Party, 1946, 1952 (Reel 5218, Frame unfilmed)
    (thank you letters, menus, and schedules)
  - New York Central, 1942-1952 (Reel 5218, Frame 546-581)
    (travel arrangements)
  - The New York City Council for Art Week, Inc., 1941 (Reel 5218, Frame 582-588)
  - New York City Department of Welfare (see: Department of Welfare, New York City) (Reel 5218)
  - New York Conference for Inalienable Rights, 1941 (Reel 5218, Frame 589-602)
  - New York Council on American Soviet Relations and New York Peace Committee for April 6, 1940-1942 (Reel 5218, Frame 603-610)
    (form letters and printed matter)
  - New York Graphic Society (see: Pushman vs. New York Graphic Society) (Reel 5218)
  - New York Herald Tribune, 1941-1946 (Reel 5218, Frame 611-630)
  - New York Post, 1938, 1947 (Reel 5218, Frame 631-634)
  - The New York Public Library, 1945, 1948 (Reel 5218, Frame 635-641)
  - New York School of Art (see: Chase, William Merritt) (Reel 5218)
  - New York State Committee to Abolish the Poll Tax, 1943 (Reel 5218, Frame 642-644)
  - New York State Department of Commerce (see: Department of Commerce, State of New York) (Reel 5218)
  - New York State Electric & Gas Corporation, 1946-1947, 1952 (Reel 5218, Frame 645-653)
  - New York State Historical Association, undated, 1949, 1951, 1966 (Reel 5218, Frame 654-663)
  - New York State Police, 1949 (Reel 5218, Frame 664-666)
  - New York Telephone Company, 1941 (Reel 5218, Frame 667-670)
  - The New York Times, 1934-1936, 1942 (Reel 5218, Frame 671-685)
  - New York World, 1927 (Reel 5218, Frame 686-688)
  - New York World Telegram, 1941 (Reel 5218, Frame 689-691)
  - The New Yorker, 1941, 1943 (Reel 5218, Frame 692-697)
  - Newark Beth Israel Hospital, 1941 (Reel 5218, Frame 698-702)
  - Newark Peace Action Committee, 1941 (Reel 5218, Frame 703-706)
  - Newell-Emmett Company, 1942 (Reel 5218, Frame 707-710)